handymanclub.com 2014-04-07

# Privacy Policy

**********PRIVACY POLICY**

Last updated on January 1, 2013

  **SCOUT**

In addition to reviewing this Privacy Policy, please read our Terms of Service. Your use of this website constitutes agreement to the terms and conditions of those Terms of Service and your consent to the collection and use of information from you as described in this Privacy Policy. 

WE ARE COMMITTED TO PROTECTING THE PRIVACY OF CHILDREN. THE WEBSITES LINKING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY ARE NOT DIRECTED AT CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 18 AND ARE NOT INTENDED FOR USE BY THOSE UNDER 18.  IF YOU ARE UNDER 18, YOU MAY NOT PROVIDE ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION ON THE WEBSITES. WE WILL NOT KNOWINGLY OR INTENTIONALLY COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION ONLINE FROM CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 18.

SCOUT values the relationship we have with our members and we are committed to responsible information handling practices. We have adopted and implemented this Privacy Policy as part of our commitment to protecting your personal information from misuse.

  This Privacy Policy applies to our information-gathering and dissemination practices for all websites that contain a link to this Privacy Policy including without limitation the following sites (hereinafter referred to collectively as the “Websites”): 

•   North American Hunting Club (huntingclub.com) 

•   North American Fishing Club (fishingclub.com) 

•   Handyman Club of America (handymanclub.com) 

•   National Home Gardening Club (gardeningclub.com) 

•   Golf Partners Club (golfpartnersclub.com) 

•   Cooking Club of America (cookingclub.com) 

•   National Health & Wellness Club (healthandwellnessclub.com) 

•   Creative Home Arts Club (creativehomeartsclub.com) 

•   The History Channel Club (thehistorychannelclub.com) 

•   Motorcycle Riders Club of America (motorcycleridersclubofamerica.com) 

•   MLB Insiders Club (mlbinsidersclub.com) 

•   SCOUT (SCOUTinc.com) 

•   StuffStuff (StuffStuff.com) 

SCOUT’s Websites may contain links to other websites not operated by SCOUT.  SCOUT is not responsible for the information practices or the content of such other websites.  SCOUT encourages you to review the privacy statements of such other websites to understand their information practices.

**UNITED STATES ONLY**

The Websites are intended for use by residents of the United States of America only. All matters relating to The Websites are governed by the laws of the State of Minnesota in the United States of America. If you are located outside of the United States of America and you contact us, please be advised that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States of America and that by submitting information, you explicitly authorize its transfer.

**THE TYPE OF INFORMATION THAT SCOUT COLLECTS ONLINE**

INFORMATION PROVIDED BY YOU

SCOUT generally collects personally identifying information with your specific knowledge and consent. For instance, when you enroll in a club, enter a sweepstakes or contest, complete a survey, make a purchase, or register for any portion of our services, you are asked to provide information such as your e-mail address, mailing address, name or phone number. Optional information such as your age or gender may also be requested. 

Users of forums and message/bulletin boards that may be on the Websites should be aware that when they voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information (e.g., name, e-mail address, etc.) on a message/bulletin board, in a chat area, or other interactive area where personal information can be posted, the information can be collected and used by other internet users. This may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or parties. We make no representations and undertake no obligations as to the security of information you voluntarily post in chat rooms and message/bulletin boards. Please refer to the Terms of Service for additional terms regarding use of these services. 

Some areas of the Websites require you to select a user name and password. Users will be responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any user name and password, and we will not be responsible for misuse of any user names or passwords by any third party, whether authorized by a user or not. 

**CLICK STREAM INFORMATION; IP ADDRESS AND SYSTEM INFORMATION; COOKIES AND BEACONS**

Our web server automatically collects click-stream information such as the address (or "URL") of the website that you came from before visiting our site, which pages you visit on our site, which browser you used to view our site and any search terms you have entered on our site.

  Whenever you request a page from the Websites your IP address, browser and version, operating system, and the site from which you came are collected by SCOUT.  

SCOUT and advertisers on the Websites may also use Cookies, but SCOUT does not have control over Cookies placed by advertisers and you must consult the privacy policies of those advertisers for information related to their information collection practices.  "Cookies" are small text files a website can use to recognize repeat users, facilitate users' ongoing access to and use of the site and allow tracking of usage behavior.  If you do not want non-personal information about your visits collected through the use of Cookies, you may set your computer to deny or accept the Cookie feature through a simple process in most browsers; however, without Cookies we may be unable to provide you with certain features (e.g., customized or personalized delivery of information) otherwise available on the Websites.  

SCOUT may use web beacons alone or in conjunction with Cookies to compile information about your usage of the Websites and interaction with e-mails from SCOUT. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as Cookies, when you viewed a particular Website tied to the web beacon, and a description of a Website tied to the web beacon. For example, SCOUT may place web beacons in e-mails that notify SCOUT when you click on a link in the e-mail that directs you to one of the Websites. SCOUT may use web beacons to operate and improve the Websites and e-mail communications. SCOUT may use information from web beacons in combination with information you provide to SCOUT to provide you with information about SCOUT and its products and services.

Hereinafter the data collected under this CLICK STREAM INFORMATION; IP ADDRESS AND SYSTEM INFORMATION; COOKIES AND BEACONS section of this Privacy Policy shall be known collectively as “Website Navigational Information.”

**SEND-TO-A-FRIEND TOOLS**

The Websites may, from time to time, include a send-to-a-friend application that makes it easy for you to forward information or materials from the Websites to friends or family by e-mail. In order to address your e-mail message, the application will ask you to input the recipient’s e-mail address and/or similar information (including your e-mail address) (collectively “Send-To-A-Friend Information”).  

**HOW SCOUT USES INFORMATION PROVIDED BY YOU**

We use the information you provide in order to 1) fulfill requests for products, services or information, 2) administer your membership accounts, 3) provide member services, 4) administer contests or promotions, 5) offer new products and services, 6) measure and improve the effectiveness of our websites or our marketing endeavors, 7) tailor our online offerings to your preferences, and 8) other business purposes. 

  We may combine personal information that you provide to us online with outside records to enhance our ability to market products or provide services that we believe may be of interest to you. In addition, we may share your information with our affiliates and with carefully selected companies who we think can offer you services and products of interest to you. 

Except as provided herein and so long as you activate your membership, SCOUT will not sell to any third party your e-mail address unless you provide your informed consent.  Your informed consent shall be in the form of an "opt in" or similar policy. 

We share aggregated data (information that does not identify you) with third parties.  For example and without limitation, SCOUT may disclose to third parties your zip code, gender and/or age, but only in the form of aggregated information. 

Except as otherwise stated herein, Website Navigational Information is generally used for statistical purposes in order to improve the Websites including diagnosing problems with the Websites and their servers, provide accurate statistics to track usage on the Websites, and to provide targeted advertising. 

Send-To-A-Friend information is only used by the application to address your message so that it can be properly sent. SCOUT does not retain any Send-To-A-Friend Information for any other purpose.

We reserve the right to offer you third party services and products based on the preferences that you identify during the registration process or from information gathered from surveys and based on your subsequent preferences; such offers may be provided to you by SCOUT.

  We reserve the right to terminate your account if we learn that you have provided SCOUT with false or misleading registration information.

  We may also disclose users' personal information if we believe that we are required to do so (i) by law, (ii) to comply with legal process or governmental requests, (iii) to enforce our Terms of Service, or (iv) to protect the rights, property, or safety of SCOUT, its users or the public.

  SCOUT may assign, sell, license, or otherwise transfer to a third party, all information collected from or in relation to you in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture, or other transfer or disposition of a portion or all of the assets or stock of SCOUT or its affiliated entities.

**THIRD PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS**

We work with third parties who provide services including but not limited to website hosting, order processing and fulfillment, credit card clearance, e-commerce affiliation, data analysis, emailing and other services of an administrative nature. Personal information, including financial information, is shared with such third parties for the purpose of providing such services.

  We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ Cookies and web beacons (also known as single pixel gifs or action tags) to measure advertising effectiveness. 

SCOUT allows access to database information by third parties providing technical services, such as e-mail, but only to the extent necessary to provide you with those services. In those instances, the third party is bound by these terms. 

**THIRD PARTY RETAILERS AND OFFERS**

Some of the Websites may from time to time work with a retailer or other third party to offer online shopping opportunities, games, services, subscriptions and other applications on a co-branded or cross-promotional basis. Those transactions may take place on a Website, or the site of the third party. In either case, personal information you provide in connection with the transaction may be shared with the third party, as well as with any participating sponsors or advertisers of such opportunities and features. 

**SECURITY**

SCOUT maintains practices and procedures designed to ensure the security, integrity and confidentiality of personal information collection through the Websites.  A firewall protects the e-mail server to which all personal information is delivered.  Access to the information is limited to those employees and contractors who need it to carry out their business functions.  SCOUT's employees are educated about the importance of safeguarding personal information and preventing unauthorized access, disclosure and use.  Finally, we use secure server software ("SSL") that encrypts credit card information (including your name and address) submitted to any of the Websites. 

**OPT-OUT**

You may inform us if you wish to remove your personal information from our database, and we will comply with your request as soon as reasonably possible. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes, and there may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records. We reserve the right, from time to time, to re-contact former users of the Websites.

  We give you the following options for removing your personal information from our database in order to stop receiving future communications from the Websites.

  1\. Follow directions on a marketing e-mail or direct mail communication from us regarding the removal of your personal information from our database. 

2\. You can send your request via e-mail to the club-specific website: 

•   Creative Home Arts Club = [memberservices@creativehomeartsclub.com ](mailto:memberservices@creativehomeartsclub.com)

•   MLB Insider Club = [memberservices@baseballinsidersclub.com](mailto:memberservices@baseballinsidersclub.com)

  •   Cooking Club of America = [memberservices@cookingclub.com](mailto:memberservices@cookingclub.com)

  •   Handyman Club of America = [memberservices@handymanclub.com](mailto:memberservices@handymanclub.com)

  •   North American Fishing Club = [memberservices@fishingclub.com](mailto:memberservices@fishingclub.com)

  •   National Home Gardening Club = [memberservices@gardeningclub.com](mailto:memberservices@gardeningclub.com)

  •   North American Hunting Club = [memberservices@huntingclub.com](mailto:memberservices@huntingclub.com)

  •   The History Channel Club = [memberservices@thehistorychannelclub.com](mailto:memberservices@thehistorychannelclub.com)

  •   Motorcycle Riders Club of America = [memberservices@ridersclubofamerica.com](mailto:memberservices@ridersclubofamerica.com)

  •   Golf Partners Club = [memberservice@golfpartnersclub.com](mailto:memberservice@golfpartnersclub.com)

  •   National Street Machine Club = [memberservices@streetmachineclub.com](mailto:memberservices@streetmachineclub.com)

  •   National Health & Wellness Club = [memberservices@healthandwellnessclub.com](mailto:memberservices@healthandwellnessclub.com)

  •   StuffStuff = [support@stuffstuff.com  
](mailto:support@stuffstuff.com)  
3\. You can send your request via e-mail to [optout@scout.com](mailto:optout@scout.com).    

4\. You can send your request via U.S. Postal Service to the following mailing address.  As indicated, please provide the specific club name in the first line of the address:

  [insert club name]  
P.O. Box 1108  
Charlotte, NC 28201-1207

  Please note: We are not responsible for removing information from third-party lists or entities with which we have shared your information pursuant to this policy.

  **YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Customers residing in California may submit a request for disclosure of (1) the categories of personal information that we may share with third parties, and (2) a list of the names and addresses of all third parties with whom we have shared such information for their marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. To request this information, please submit a request to:  

**UPDATING OR CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION**

Changes to personal information can be made by sending a request via e-mail or US mail to the addresses noted above under OPT-OUT.

**CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Websites, or your dealings with us, please feel free to contact us at:

  SCOUT   
12301 Whitewater Drive  
 Minnetonka, MN 55343

  **REVISIONS TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any of the policies or procedures in this Privacy Policy may be changed at any time without prior notice. You can determine if this Privacy Policy has been revised by referring to the "Last Updated" date at the top of this page. Use of the Websites constitutes your acceptance of the terms of our Privacy Policy then in effect. We encourage you to bookmark this page and to periodically review it to ensure familiarity with the most current version of our Privacy Policy.
